Aashish Balaji

🛮 aashish.balaji1@live.com 🌎 aashish-b 🔭 https://aashishb.github.io 👂 Toronto, Canada

Profile

I'm a software engineer based in Toronto and I co-created Triage \mathscr{D} , a Kafka consumer proxy built for polyglot microservice environments. I have multiple years of experience working with Go, JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, and am also versed in AWS and Docker. I love producing music, reading/writing, building PCs, and badminton. I also enjoy working on challenging problems with strong, focused teams.

Skills

Languages

Go, JavaScript, SQL, Ruby, HTML/CSS

Databases & Cloud

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS (EC2, ECS, IAM, CloudWatch, CloudFormation, Fargate), DigitalOcean, Heroku

Frameworks & Libraries

React, jQuery, Express.js, Node.js

Tooling & Networking

Git, Docker, gRPC, HTTP/REST

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer,

Triage (https://team-triage.github.io/) ∂

• Developed an open-source proxy for Apache Kafka consumers, written in Go.

- Led implementation of a gRPC service using protocol buffers for Triage to communicate with downstream consumer applications.
- Designed components and database schema to aggregate data from incoming events and store corrupted messages using Amazon's DynamoDB.
- Automated an infrastructure deployment strategy using AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK).
- Led Docker containerization of our service for successful deployment to an Amazon ECS cluster.
- Built a CLI tool in JS (published on NPM) that manages Kafka configuration and authentication, deploys our service to AWS, and handles teardown.
- Authored and edited a technical case study to showcase our design and architecture https://team-triage.github.io/case-study

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2021 - 2022

2022 - present

- Request-Djinn An HTTP webhook inspector built using a MERN stack and PostgreSQL, hosted on a DO Droplet.
- Shopping Cart A Docker containerized e-commerce app built with JS, Express, and MongoDB.
- Contact Manager a single page application with filtering and tagging built with jQuery, Handlebars, and JavaScript.
- Todo List a task tracker built using Ruby, Sinatra, and PostgreSQL.

English Teacher, Seijo High School ∂

2015 - 2021 | Tokyo, Japan

- Designed curricula for ESL and English immersion classes for Japanese high school students in grades 6-12.
- Taught grammar, writing, and debate classes in both solo and team-teaching styles.
- Trained and assisted newer English teachers with lesson planning, grading, and communication.

Education

Software Engineering, Launch School *⊘*

2021 - 2022

Mastery-based full-stack software engineering program with a focus on programming fundamentals through written assessments, live coding interviews, and take-home projects.